Inventory of the Papers of Richard B. Lillich, 1927 [1957-1996]-1996
University of Virginia, Arthur J. Morris Law Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Law Library
Papers of Richard B. Lillich, 1927 [1957-1996]-1996
Special Collections, University of Virginia Law Library
MSS 97-1
This collection consists of 73 boxes (30 linear feet).
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Biographical/Historical Information
Richard B. Lillich, Howard W. Smith Professor of Law at the University of Virginia and Edward Ball Eminent Scholar Chair in International Law at the Florida State University College of Law, was born January 22, 1933 in Amherst, Ohio. He received his bachelor's degree from Oberlin College in 1954; his LL.B from Cornell Law School in 1957, with a specialization in International Affairs; and his LL.M and J.S.D from New York University School of Law in 1960, with a specialization in International Law.
Lillich was admitted to the New York Bar in 1957. He practiced private law until 1960 and then joined Syracuse University College of Law where he was a professor and director of International Legal Studies until 1969. He came to the University of Virginia that same year and was named Howard W. Smith Professor in 1977. In 1994 he was named Visiting Edward Ball Eminent Scholar Chair in International Law at Florida State University College of Law. He held both of these positions until his death. In addition he was a visiting professor or fellow at many prestigious institutions, including the United States Naval War College; the Centre for International Studies, Cambridge, England; New York University School of Law; All Souls College, Oxford, England; the Max-Planck Institute, Heidelberg, Germany; University of Georgia School of Law; and St. Louis University School of Law.
A prominent scholar of international law, Lillich published more than 30 books and scores of articles. He was a longtime, active leader in the American Society of International Law and served for many years on the editorial board of the American Journal of International Law. He was President of Procedural Aspects of International Law Institute, a group of international law scholars and practitioners he helped establish in 1965. Other memberships include the American Law Institute, the Association of the Bar of the City of New York, the British Institute of International and Comparative Law, the International Law Association. As an active lawyer preoccupied with human rights problems worldwide, he served on the advisory boards of a number of international groups focusing on these problems, including the International Human Rights Law Group which he helped to found in 1978. His national service included consultation for the U. S. Naval War College and the Department of State in the Iran-United States Claims Tribunal.
Lillich died suddenly of a heart attack while working at his Albemarle County farm on August 3, 1996.
Scope and Content Information
The collection is arranged in five series based upon Lillich's own arrangements: general professional files; Iran-U.S. Claims Tribunal; Sokol Colloquium; published articles; and organ transplantation, lump sum, and miscellaneous files. There is also a small collection of photographs.
Contents List
- General Professional Files
  - AJIL [American Journal of International Law] 1969-1981 (Box 1)
  - AJIL-African Distribution 1989-1995 (Box 1)
  - AJIL-Committee on the Tenure of the Board of Visitors 1984-1995 (Box 1995)
  - AJIL-Correspondence, Reviews 1987-1995 (Box 1)
  - American Society of International Law Panel of State Responsibility 1982, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Avram Claim [Trans-Continental Banking Corporation, Ltd.] 1957-1965 (Box 1)
  - [Blasphemy and Prior Restraint] Lillich's Consultation 1993 (Box 2)
  - Book Review: British Claims 1968 (Box 2)
  - Book Review: International Claims: Their Adjudication by National Commissions 1962-1963 (Box 2)
  - Book Review: The Protection of Foreign Investment: Six Procedural Studies 1965-1967 (Box 2)
  - Book Review: Valuation of Nationalized Property in International Law 1973 (Box 2)
  - Book Reviews 1981-1990 (Box 2)
  - Certification of Questions to the Court of Appeals 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - Ceylon Petroleum Corporation 1964, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Claims. Rumanian Claims 1963 (Box 3)
  - Colgate Palmolive Case 1968-1970, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Correspondence A-Z 1986-1995, 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Correspondence with Naval War College 1972-1985 (Box 4)
  - Czech Claims 1964-1981 (Box 4)
  - Department of Justice. Human Rights Project 1926-1971, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Department of Justice. Human Rights Project II. Texts of Statutes, Executive Orders, Regulations, Guidelines, Interagency Agreements 1961-1968, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Department of Justice. Human Rights Project. Civil Rights Decision. Memoranda 1975-1976 (Box 5)
  - Department of State. Foreign Claims Settlement Commission 1977-1983 (Box 5)
  - Department of State. Gut Dam Claims 1963-1965 (Box 5)
  - Department of State. International Claims 1975-1981 (Box 6)
  - Dillard's Papers 1982-1984 (Box 6)
  - Domestic Courts. Reference Materials 1971-1982, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Exxon v. USA (Claims Court 235-79T) Related to Cuba 1984 (Box 7)
  - Extradition. Michele Sindona Requested Extradition by the Republic of Italy 1977, 8 folders (Box 8-10)
  - Extradition. USA v. Mulette, et al 1978 (Box 8-10)
  - Festschrift, Bernhart [Human Rights, Zimbabwe, Jamaica] 1984-1994 (Box 8-10)
  - Fiji 1990-1991 (Box 8-10)
  - Ford Foundation 1981-1982 (Box 8-10)
  - Foreign Claims Settlement Commission 1992-1993 (Box 8-10)
  - Foundation of Japanese Honorary Debts [Stichting Japanese Ereschulden]. Correspondence with Dr. Gerard Junslager and Theo van Boven 1995-1996 (Box 11)
  - FSU [Florida State University] Ball Lectures 1996 (Box 11)
  - FSU Correspondence with Dean Weidner 1992-1996 (Box 11)
  - FSU Correspondence with UVA Dean Robert E. Scott 1995-1996 (Box 11)
  - FSU Correspondence with Dean Donna R. Christie 1995 (Box 11)
  - FSU Journal of Transnational Law and Policy. Correspondence 1996 (Box 11)
  - FSU Miscellaneous Papers 1995-1996 (Box 11)
  - FSU Re: Prof. Garcia 1995 (Box 11)
  - Georgia. University of Georgia General 1992 (Box 11)
  - Gubbay, Justice A. [Chief Justice of Zimbabwe] Correspondence. 1995 (Box 11)
  - Harpum, Charles Correspondence 1990-1992 (Box 11)
  - Heidelburg Correspondence 1990-1993 (Box 11)
  - Hong Kong [Bill of Rights] 1992-1993 (Box 11)
  - Human Rights. American Convention on Human Rights 1994 (Box 12)
  - Human Rights. Annotated Miscellaneous Human Rights Cases 1980s (Box 12)
  - Human Rights. Botswana. In the matter between Unity Dow and the Attorney General of Botswana. Brief of the Urban Morgan Institute for Human Rights, University of Cincinnati College of Law 1990 (Box 12)
  - Human Rights. Convention on the Elimination of All Forms of Discrimination Against Women 1980, 1994 (Box 12)
  - Human Rights. Daugherty, Scarlet et al v. Terry A. Wallace. Brief of the Urban Morgan Institute for Human Rights, University of Cincinnati College of Law as Amicus Curiae 1992 (Box 12)
  - Human Rights. Dellums, Ronald v. Eleanor Ginsberg, Myrna Cunningham v. William French Smith, individually and in his official capacity as Attorney General of the U.S. [U.S. Government Officials Violation of the Neutrality Act] 1983 (Box 12)
  - Human Rights. European Court of Human Rights. Peter Michaels Lingens against Austria 1984-1985 (Box 12)
  - Human Rights. Re: Extradition of John Demjanjuk. Brief of Amicus Curiae. The International Human Rights Law Group [Israel] 1984 (Box 12)
  - Human Rights. Fernandez-Roque, Rafael et al v. William French Smith; Moises Garcia-Mir, et al v. William French Smith; Chao-Estrada, Orlando v. William French Smith 1985 (Box 13)
  - Human Rights. Filartiga v. Pena-Irala [Paraguay] 1979-1981 (Box 13)
  - Human Rights. Garza, Jasper et al v. Billy Reagan, et al. Brief of the International Human Rights Group as Amicus Curiae in Support of Plaintiffs. [Re: Denial of Free Public Education to Illegal Children] 1979 (Box 13)
  - Human Rights. "Human Rights of Aliens in Europe" 1980-1983 (Box 13)
  - Human Rights. International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights 1995 (Box 13)
  - Human Rights. Jean, Marie Lucie et al v. Alan C. Nelson, et al 1984 (Box 14)
  - Human Rights. Lillich's International Human Rights Treaties and Agreement Report 1979 (Box 14)
  - Human Rights. Marcos [Ferdinand A., Philippines] Cases: Sison, Trajano, Hilao, Ortigas, Clemente 1982, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Human Rights Miscellaneous Cases 1984-1996, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Human Rights. In the matter of The New York Times Co. v. The New York Commission of Human Rights and American Committee on Africa, African Heritage Studies Association, One Hundred Black Men, Inc. and William Booth 1972-1975 (Box 15)
  - Human Rights. Otto Preminger Institute v. Austria 1993 (Box 15)
  - Human Rights. Race Convention 1994 (Box 15)
  - Human Rights. Rodriguez Fernandez, Pedro v. George C. Wilkinson 1980-1981 (Box 15)
  - Human Rights. Hanock Tel-Oren, et al v. Libyan Arab Republic, et al 1981-1984 (Box 15)
  - Human Rights. The Torture Victim Protection Act of 1985 Briefing Book 1985 (Box 15)
  - Human Rights. Texas School Children's Case 1974-1980, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Human Rights. USA v. Humberto Alvarez-Machain 1990 (Box 16)
  - Institute of International Criminal Law 1981-1982 (Box 17)
  - ICJ [International Court of Justice] Correspondence 1975-1984 (Box 17)
  - ICJ Aegean Case; Cold War Decision; Nuclear Testing Clippings 1972-1973 (Box 17)
  - ICJ Interviews 1975 (Box 17)
  - ICJ Project 1981 (Box 17)
  - ICJ Research Proposal n.d. (Box 17)
  - ICJ. USA v. Italy (Case Concerning Elettronica Sicula, SPA ELSI) Ratheon Case 1986-1990, 10 folders and 5 bounded notebooks (Box 18-20)
  - ICJ Western Sahara Clippings 1972-1973 (Box 18-20)
  - ILA [International Law Assocation] American Branch. Constitution of the Association, Committees 1995-1996 (Box 21)
  - ILA American Branch Correspondence 1984-1996 (Box 21)
  - ILA American Branch. Correspondence with Alfred P. Rubin, Edward Gordon, Cynthia Crawford Liechtenstein 1994-1996 (Box 21)
  - ILA American Branch Executive Committee 1986-1995 (Box 21)
  - ILA Committee on Human Rights. Correspondence with Mrs. B. Osorio 1995-1996 (Box 21)
  - ILA Committee on Enforcement of Human Rights. Correspondence with Hurst Hannum 1990-1991 (Box 21)
  - Committee on International Human Rights. Correspondence with Anne Bayefsky, Mathias Herdergen, Menno T. Kamminga, Eckart Klein 1996 (Box 21)
  - ILA Committee on International Human Rights. Universal Jurisdiction [Diskette] 1995 (Box 21)
  - ILA Committee on International Human Rights Sanctions 1995-1996 (Box 21)
  - ILA 66th Conference of the International Law Association, Buenos Aires 1994-1995 (Box 21)
  - ILA Correspondence 1990-1996 (Box 21)
  - ILA Correspondence with Ian Brownlie, Q.C. 1982-1992 (Box 21)
  - ILA Director of Studies Report 1991-1996 (Box 21)
  - ILA Executive Council Minutes 1982-1985, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Interights [International Centre for the Legal Protection of Human Rights] 1994-1996 (Box 22)
  - Interights Advisory Council Meetings 1984-1995 (Box 22)
  - Interights. Lester, Anthony Correspondence 1983-1996 (Box 22)
  - Interights Reports 1982-1995 (Box 22)
  - Iran v. USA 1988-1989 (Box 23)
  - Justice Department 1993-1996 (Box 23)
  - Law School Correspondence 1994 (Box 23)
  - Law School-Dean Scott Correspondence, Memos 1990-1996 (Box 23)
  - Law School-Dean Jackson 1989-1992 (Box 23)
  - Law School. Faculty "Banking" Program 1988-1991 (Box 23)
  - Law School-Ford Foundation Final Report 1991-1992 (Box 23)
  - Law School-Ford Foundation Grants 1991-1993, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Law School- Ford Foundation International Law Grant 1990 (Box 24)
  - Law School Graduate Program Correspondence 1990-1993 (Box 24)
  - Law School Graduate Program-General. Proposal for an Asylum and Refugee Law Clinic 1986-1996 (Box 24)
  - Law School-Elaine Hadden Correspondence 1993-1995 (Box 24)
  - Law School International Human Rights Law Clinic 1984-1986 (Box 24)
  - Law School-Iwasawa Correspondence 1987-1996 (Box 24)
  - Law School. Lillich's Reports 1986-1996, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Law School. Lillich's Seminars on Human Rights 1983-1990 (Box 24)
  - Law School-David Martin Correspondence 1993 (Box 25)
  - Law School-Richard Merrill Correspondence 1985-1988 (Box 25)
  - Law School-J.B. Moore Society of International Law 1995 (Box 25)
  - Law School-John N. Moore 1995 (Box 25)
  - Law School. Private International Law 1979-1980 (Box 25)
  - Lesotho 1981-1982 (Box 25)
  - Malpractice 1961 (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence 1959-1975 (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous Papers 1986-1988 (Box 25)
  - Mulligan, William C. Miscellaneous Papers 1973, 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Municipal Officials and Conflicts of Interest. An Analysis of the State of the Law and a Proposed Statute. Prepared by Milton Kaplan and Richard B. Lillich 1957 (Box 25)
  - Nationalizations 1963 (Box 26)
  - Nationalizations-Department of State 1957-1962 (Box 26)
  - Nationalizations-Arab Oil Matters Clippings 1972 (Box 26)
  - Nationalizations-Chile 1971 (Box 26)
  - Nationalizations-Chile. Anaconda Company and Chile Copper Co. and Overseas Private Investment Corporation 1977 (Box 26)
  - Nationalizations-Chile Expropriation of El Teniente Copper Mine 1971-1973 (Box 26)
  - Nationalizations-China 1979 (Box 26)
  - Nationalizations-Clippings 1965-1977 (Box 26)
  - Nationalizations Clippings: Algeria, Argentina, Austria, Brazil, Ceylon, Fiji, Guyana, Iraq, Jamaica 1965-1977 (Box 26)
  - Nationalizations Clippings: Bolivia, Great Britain, Tanzania, United States, Czechoslovakia, Egypt, India 1967-1975 (Box 27)
  - Nationalizations Clippings: Nigeria, Qatar, Venezuela, Zambia, Zimbabwe 1965-1977 (Box 27)
  - Nationalizations Clippings: Poland, Portugal, Saudi Arabia, Switzerland 1967-1975 (Box 27)
  - Nationalizations Clippings: Ethiopia, France, Kuwait, Mexico, Nicaragua 1967-1975 (Box 27)
  - Nationalizations-Cuba 1954-1964 (Box 27)
  - Nationalizations-Iran 1979-1980 (Box 27)
  - Nationalizations-Lithgow Case 1986 (Box 27)
  - Nationalizations-Libya 1973-1977 (Box 27)
  - Nationalizations-Peru 1970-1977, 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Nationalizations-Yugoslavia 1964 (Box 28)
  - Naval War College. Correspondence 1970-1983 (Box 28)
  - Neff, Stephen. Correspondence 1982-1996 (Box 28)
  - New York University 1977 (Box 28)
  - Obremski, Stephen Mitchell-Foreign Claims Settlement Commission of the US [Poland Claims] 1963 (Box 28)
  - PAIL [Procedural Aspects of International Law]-Autonomy Project/Department of State 1979-1980 (Box 28)
  - PAIL Correspondence. Re: Cases 1975 (Box 29)
  - PAIL-Council of Europe Convention [Terrorism Project II] 1976-1977 (Box 29)
  - PAIL-Department of State Correspondence 1975-1978 (Box 29)
  - PAIL General Correspondence 1976-1977 (Box 29)
  - PAIL Institute-Correspondence with Consultants 1976-1977 (Box 29)
  - PAIL Memos-Aggression. "The Declaration of Aggression and State Responsibility for Terrorists Acts"; "State Responsibility for Losses Occasioned by Terrorists: An Analysis of Recent Warsaw Convention" 1976 (Box 29)
  - PAIL Memos: "The Count Bernadotte Incident and the Issue of State Responsibility"; The Declaration of Friendly Relations and State Responsibility for Terrorist Acts" 1976 (Box 29)
  - PAIL Memos-Soviet Claims 1976 (Box 29)
  - PAIL Memos-Terrorism. "The Legal Impact of Failure to Apprehend, Punish or Extradite Terrorists" 1976 (Box 29)
  - PAIL-Terrorism. Terrorism Project I 1975 (Box 29)
  - PAIL- Terrorism. "State Responsibility for Tolerating the Use of Territory for Terrorist Activities Aimed at Persons in other States" 1976 (Box 29)
  - PAIL-Terrorism. Terrorism Project II. Research Proposal and Research 1976-1977 (Box 29)
  - PAIL-Terrorism. Terrorism Project III 1977-1978 (Box 30)
  - PAIL-Terrorism. "State Responsibility for Failure to Prevent Terrorist Acts which Injure Aliens" 1976 (Box 30)
  - PAIL-Terrorism. Transnational Terrorism 1978-1982 (Box 30)
  - PAIL-Weston, Burns H. Correspondence 1966-1973, 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Private Practice. Yusuf Ahmed Alghanim & Sons, Ltd. Claim Filed with the United Nations Compensation Commission 1995 (Box 31)
  - Private Practice. AMCO Asia Corporation Case 1988 (Box 31)
  - Private Practice. Ashland Oil Company 1988-1989, 2 folders (Box 31)
  - Private Practice. Bencik Case [Human Rights Case] 1985-1986 (Box 31)
  - Private Practice. Department of State Correspondence 1986-1988 (Box 31)
  - Private Practice. Exxon Corporation v. US Government. US Claims Court 1984-1986 (Box 31)
  - Private Practice. Jewish Restitution 1994-1995, 3 folders (Box 32)
  - Private Practice. Liberian Case 1990 (Box 32)
  - Private Practice. Nicaragua v. Dole Food Company Inc. 1995 (Box 32)
  - Private Practice. Pecten Vietnam Company Claim v. The Socialist Republic of Vietnam. Lillich's Legal Opinion 1994-1995 (Box 33)
  - Private Practice. Sabi-Aryeh Case 1993-1996, 4 folders (Box 33)
  - Private Practice. Sakkis Claim 1980 (Box 34)
  - Private Practice. Ugandan Case 1985-1988 (Box 34)
  - Private Practice. Vietnam Claims 1987-1994 (Box 34)
  - Publications. Correspondence, Contracts, Miscellaneous 1966-1995 (Box 35)
  - Qatar. Wintershall, A.G. et al v. Government of Qatar 1987, 3 folders (Box 35)
  - Quantas Claim. Herzog v. Quantas Airlines Ltd. [Food Poisoning] 1967-1968 (Box 36)
  - Raboin, Michael F. Correspondence 1990-1996 (Box 36)
  - Rabinowitz, Victor. [Nationalizations. Banco National de Cuba v. Chase] 1981, 2 folders (Box 36)
  - Refugees. Impact on U.N. Refugees Convention on US Extradition Proceedings. Re: Marie Pierre, et al v. US. [Haitian Refugees] 1977, 2 folders (Box 36)
  - Rosenkranz, Joseph Claim Case 1964-1966, 3 folders (Box 37)
  - Saint Louis University School of Law 1994-1995 (Box 37)
  - Sakkis Claim [Expropriation of Land without Compensation in Mexico] 1979-1981, 3 folders (Box 38)
  - Speeches. Notes and Outlines 1962-1965 (Box 38)
  - Soering Case 1988-1995, 2 folders (Box 39)
  - Swiss Treaty Case: Christopher D. Ohly 1984-1987 (Box 39)
  - Taking Property n.d. (Box 39)
  - Toman, Jiri (Dr.) Correspondence 1984-1994 (Box 39)
  - Tudor Claim [v. Romania. Orghidan Collection] 1975-1981, 4 folders (Box 40)
  - Uganda-Expropriations. Claims for Compensation for Expropriated Property. British High Court Documents 1982-1983, 4 folders (Box 41)
  - United Kingdom All Souls College 1985-1987 (Box 42)
  - United Kingdom-Cambridge-Oxford Faculty n.d. (Box 42)
  - United Kingdom-Claims Department 1990-1994 (Box 42)
  - United Kingdom-Downing College 1980-1984 (Box 42)
  - United Kingdom-Fellowships 1973-1993 (Box 42)
  - United States Justice Department of Justice Correspondence 1979-1981 (Box 42)
  - United States Department of Justice Education Memorandum 1978 (Box 42)
  - United States Department of Justice. General 1978-1980 (Box 42)
  - United States Department of Justice Lillich's Master Copy of "The Use of International Human Rights Norms in US Corps" 1980 (Box 42)
  - United States Department of Justice. Wilmington 10 1977-1978 (Box 43)
  - United States Institute of Human Rights 1984 (Box 43)
  - United States v. Johan Breyer [International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights] 1993 (Box 43)
  - Urban Morgan Institute for Human Rights-University of Cincinnati 1982 (Box 43)
  - Wintershall v. Government of Qatar 1987 (Box 43)
  - Zambia v. United Kingdom (Mubanga-Chipoya) International Court 1983-1984 (Box 43)
  - Zambia v. Oil Companies 1977 (Box 43)
  - Zimbabwe. Newspaper Clippings 1985 (Box 43)
- Iran-U.S. Claims Tribunal
  - Abbas Ghaffari v. National Iranian Oil Company and the Islamic Republic of Iran 1982 (Box 44)
  - Annual Report 1986 (Box 44)
  - Awards 1985-1987, 3 folders (Box 44)
  - Bristish Practice 1983-1984 (Box 44)
  - Categories of Small Claims of Less than $250,000 n.d. (Box 44)
  - "Compensation for Property Loses of US Nationals Expelled from Forced to Leave Iran". Memo 1981-1982 (Box 45)
  - Continuous Nationality 1967, 1982 (Box 45)
  - Creeping Expropriations. Oral Argument n.d. (Box 45)
  - Davis, Stanley Norris v. Iran (Claim No. 10502) ca. 1986-1987 (Box 45)
  - Department of State Cables 1982-1983 (Box 45)
  - Department of State. Change Circum. [sic.] and Iranian Claims. Arbitration. Concept of Controls 1982 (Box 45)
  - Department of State Correspondence-Miscellaneous 1982 (Box 45)
  - Department of State Memo: "The Amount of Recovery in Stockholder Claims" 1983 (Box 45)
  - Department of State Memo: "The Concept of a Force Majeure in the Law of International Claims" 1982 (Box 45)
  - Department of State Memo: "The Eligibility of Nonprofit Corporations Under Article VIII (1) of the Claims Settlement Agreement" 1982 (Box 45)
  - Department of State Memo: "Employment Contract Claims" 1982 (Box 45)
  - Department of State Memo: "Ethiopian Case" 1982 (Box 46)
  - Department of State Memo: "Interest Before the Iran-U.S. Claims Tribunal" 1982 (Box 46)
  - Department of State Memos: "The Applicability of Municipal Statutes of Limitation to Claims Before the Iran-U.S. Claims Tribunal"; "The Eligibility of Indirect Stockholder Claimants under the Claims Settlement Agreement" 1983 (Box 46)
  - Department of State Memos: "Compensation and Valuation in Expropriation Claims: A Framework for Future Inquiry"; Compensation for Costs and Attorneys Fees"; "The Continuous Nationality Rate and its Application to Claimants Before the Iran-U.S. Claims Tribunal" 1982 (Box 46)
  - Department of State Research Materials 1982, 4 folders (Box 46)
  - Department of State-State Responsibility 1982 (Box 47)
  - Ebrahimi, Cecilia Radene and Christina Tandis Ebrahimi v. Iran (Cases Nos. 44, 46, 47) 1994 (Box 47)
  - Electronic Data Systems, Iran v. the Social Security Organization of the Government of Iran and Marine Midland Bank 1979 (Box 47)
  - Expropriation Notes 1986 (Box 47)
  - Foreign Claims Settlement Commission [FCSC] Vietnamese Claims 1985 (Box 47)
  - Gabay v. Iran (Claim No. 771) (Re: Dominant-Effective Nationality) 1982-1983 (Box 47)
  - Government of Iran, Ministry of Mines & Metals & National Steel v. National Iranian Oil and Iran 1982, 2 folders (Box 47)
  - Hostages Related 1981 (Box 47)
  - Miscellaneous Cases 1995 (Box 47)
  - Iran v. US (Claim No. A/15) 1987, 1992, 2 folders (Box 48)
  - Iran v. US (Claim No. A-18). Memorial of the Islamic Republic of Islam on the Issue of Claims Brought by Iranians Taking Advantage of American Nationality 1983 (Box 48)
  - Iran v. US (Claim No. A/19) 1987 (Box 48)
  - Iran v. US (Case No. A/21) 1986-1987, 2 folders (Box 49)
  - Iran v. US (Case No. A/22) 1986 (Box 49)
  - Iran v. US Case B/1 (Claim 4) 1987, 3 folders (Box 49)
  - Iran v. US (Claim B/58) (The Islamic Republic of Iran Railways) 1982-1990, 3 folders (Box 50)
  - Iran Aircraft Industries, et al v. AVCO Corporation. Brief 1992 (Box 50)
  - Index of Contents for Strategy Meeting on 29th July/30th July 1991 at Alsop Wilkinson, London 1991 (Box 50)
  - Index to Issues Addressed by the Tribunal 1986 (Box 51)
  - Iranian Claims 1985 (Box 51)
  - Joint Venture Claims. Lillich's Opinions 1985 (Box 51)
  - Kiaie v. Iran 1982 (Box 51)
  - Lillich's Miscellaneous Short Memos 1982 (Box 51)
  - Louis-State Department. The Algiers Agreements of January 19, 1981 1981 (Box 51)
  - Leach, Jimmie B. v. Iran 1988, 3 folders (Box 51)
  - McCollough & Co., Inc. v. the Ministry Post, Telegraph and Telephone, the National Iranian Oil Co. and Bank Markazi 1986 (Box 52)
  - Memorandum Re: "Going-Concern Value as the Proper Measure of Compensation or Damages in International Expropriation or Breach-of-Contract Cases Involving Ongoing Businesses or Contract or Concession Rights" 1981 (Box 52)